Guide to the Schuleman / Sherman Family Papers, 1911-2018 MS 960
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Schuleman / Sherman Family Papers
1911-2018
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sherman, Barbara Elaine
MS 960
.50 Linear Feet 1 box
The collection contains news clippings, certificates, photographs, media, and San Jacinto High School and University of Texas materials, including an El Oroso signed by Walter Cronkite, which document the lives of some of the Schuleman family from 1911 to 2018.
Biographical / Historical
Minnie Wertheimer was born in Houston, April 27, 1889. She married George Schuleman in 1911 and had several children, including Israel and Schoel Schuleman, on April 10, 1921, and July 2, 1927, respectively. Israel grew up in Houston and graduated from San Jacinto High School in 1938. He graduated from Rice University in 1942, Pre-Med, and went on to the University of Texas Medical School, graduating in 1945. He was in private practice in Houston until his death at the age of 53, January 12, 1975.
Content Description
One box containing news clippings, certificates, photographs, media, and San Jacinto High School and University of Texas materials, including an El Oroso signed by Walter Cronkite, documents the lives of some of the Schuleman family from 1911 to 2018, with the bulk of the materials spanning the 1930s to 1980s.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated by Barbara Sherman in March 2021.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged into four series as follows: Series I: San Jacinto High School Materials, Series II: Family History, Series III: University of Texas Materials, and Series IV: Newspaper Clippings.
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Sherman, Barbara Elaine
- Series I: San Jacinto High School Materials
  - San Jacinto High School Class of 1933 Commencement/Yearbook (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - San Jacinto "The Campus Cub" Newspaper Clippings, 1933-2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - San Jacinto High School Class of 1933 Reunion Materials, 1973-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - San Jacinto High School-related Newspaper Clippings from Houston Papers, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - San Jacinto HS Class of 1933 reunion (VHS), 1988-05-28 (Box 1)
  - San Jacinto HS 40th Reunion (audio cassette), 1973 (Box 1)
- Series II: Family History
  - Minnie and George Schuleman Marriage Certificate, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family Photos, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minnie and George Schuleman 50th Wedding Anniversary Materials, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III: University of Texas Materials
  - University of Texas Cactus Yearbook, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - University of Texas Commencement Program, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Newspaper Clippings
  - Dr.Henry Barnston Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Jewish History in Wharton and Bay City Newspaper Clippings, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 11)